The true story of a love that shook an empire
A United Kingdom is a drama, history film directed by Amma Asante.
The inspiring true story of Seretse Khama, the King of Bechuanaland (modern Botswana), and Ruth Williams, the London office worker he
married in 1948 in the face of fierce opposition from their families and the British and South African governments.
Seretse and Ruth defied family, Apartheid and empire - their love triumphed over every obstacle flung
in their path and in so doing they transformed their nation and inspired the world.
Seretse Khama, played by David Oyelowo.
Ruth Williams-Khama, played by Rosamund Pike.
Rufus Lancaster, played by Tom Felton.
Sir Alistair Canning, played by Jack Davenport.
Naledi Khama, played by Terry Pheto.
Muriel Williams, played by Laura Carmichael.
Events from the year 2016 in the United Kingdom.
The year was dominated by the UK's vote to leave the European
Union and the subsequent political fallout.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, africa,
marriage, biography, based on true story.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.